<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tips Tricks &amp; Quick Fix</title>
    <description>Tips Tricks &amp; Quick Fix by &lt;a href=&#39;http://twitter.com/pietropassarell&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;@pietropassarell&lt;/a&gt;i.</description>
    <link></link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title></title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://pietropassarelli.gitbooks.io/how-to-tell-compelling-stories-out-of-video-inter/content/paper-editing/key-concepts-in-documentary-theory.html&quot;&gt;is an extract&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gitbook.com/book/pietropassarelli/how-to-tell-compelling-stories-out-of-video-inter/details&quot;&gt;gitbook ‘how to tell compelling stories out of video interviews’&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;!-- TODO: add bibliography at the end using UCL sytem. --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are different styles and approaches on how to make a documentary. This section aims to address questions that are often reaised a round supposed objectivity or subjectivity of the medium and it’s limitations for knowledge discovery and knowledge sharing, and proposes to provide some different perspective to examine the problem from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What follows is the bare minimum (I think) you need to know about documentary films history and theory, if you work with audio/visual medium. I draw and expand on an essay I wrote during my MA in doc films a while back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might be over simplifying here, but I think there are three main concepts that are worth knowing about when it comes to documentary films history and theory, especially if you are working in documentary or factual production, or even in some other form of story telling for that matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One is the American concept of &lt;em&gt;Direct Cinema&lt;/em&gt; (equivalent to &lt;em&gt;free cinema&lt;/em&gt; in the UK), Second one is the French idea of &lt;em&gt;Cinema Verite&lt;/em&gt;, and last but not least Verner Herzog’s concept of &lt;em&gt;Aesthetic truth&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pics.filmaffinity.com/capturing_reality-403395144-large.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Capturing reality &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But rather then dive straight into the key historic moments, it might be worth whatching &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nfb.ca/film/capturing_reality/trailer/the_art_of_documentary_trailer&quot;&gt;Capturing reality&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nfb.ca/film/capturing_reality&quot;&gt;NFBC&lt;/a&gt; beforehand to get a bit of context, here’s the trailer, that lays out some of the key issues a round documentary films, with interview with established documentary film-makers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Capturing reality trailer --&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lPavxiKKT2w&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;!-- ## Spoiler Notice --&gt;

&lt;!-- List of films with thumnbnails, --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;early-days&quot;&gt;Early Days&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;magic-lanterns&quot;&gt;Magic Lanterns&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we dive into it, it’s worth considering that it’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/10354481&quot;&gt;in infancies, documentaries, started as slide-shows of travel expeditions&lt;/a&gt;, lectures, travelogues, where the explore would narrate over his slide show in front of a live audience. Crafting it into a compelling story as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pietropassarelli.gitbooks.io/how-to-tell-compelling-stories-out-of-video-inter/content/assets/omlj-dvd-cover.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Magic Lantern movies&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magic lanterns where used as projectors to entrataine audiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
![Magic Lantern device](http://www.projectionscreen.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/magic-lantern.png)


![Magic lantern image example](http://i.ebayimg.com/images/g/dMEAAOxy0QBSSc6o/s-l300.jpg)
--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See how in this BBC documentary it is compared to a precoursour of early days cinema.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kPTL_IxLtU0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting to see how this tradition is still very much alive in what are now called “digital stories” or “Multimedia slide shows” such as those made by &lt;a href=&quot;http://mediastorm.com/pub/projects&quot;&gt;MediaStorm&lt;/a&gt;, see &lt;a href=&quot;http://mediastorm.com/training/one-man-brand&quot;&gt;One Man Brand&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://mediastorm.com/training/remember-these-days&quot;&gt;Remember These Days&lt;/a&gt; as examples. They still use a bit of video footage, but the audio interview in the narration and the stills are mostly what drives the narrative, as opposed to on screen &lt;em&gt;actuality&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another example that resonate with this tradition I think is &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/An_Inconvenient_Truth&quot;&gt;An inconvenient truth&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/Bu6SE5TYrCM&quot;&gt;trailer&lt;/a&gt;. Where at the core a lecture by Al Gore is mixed with a voiceover to ad a personal journey element to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/3/33/Nanook_of_the_north.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nanook of the north&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going back to our fast track history of docs, In &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_J._Flaherty&quot;&gt;Flaherty&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nanook_of_the_North&quot;&gt;Nanook of the North&lt;/a&gt;, he draws on the travelogue tradition. However the narrative was highly crafted during production, staging scenes and sequences, but without voice over narration, perhaps mostly due to limitations of the medium, and presented to the audience as filmed in an observational unobtrusive way. And some could argue that this created a precedent for most of the misconceptions about the camera’s supposed objectivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Nanook of the North --&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/m4kOIzMqso0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dziga-vertov-and-kino-pravda-cinema-truth&quot;&gt;Dziga Vertov and Kino-Pravda &lt;em&gt;(“Cinema Truth”)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 1920’s influence of futurism we see Dziga Vertov’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Man_with_a_Movie_Camera&quot;&gt;“Man with a Movie Camera”&lt;/a&gt; drawing from the tradition of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Documentary_film#The_city_symphony&quot;&gt;city symphony&lt;/a&gt; and really pushing the creative possibility of editing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s much more to be said about Dziga Vertov and Kino-Pravda (“Cinema Truth”) but for now, just watch it and see how it substains your attention and creates a narrative, without a voice over or dialogue…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Dziga Vertov --&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/z97Pa0ICpn8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;direct-cinema&quot;&gt;Direct Cinema&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Direct_Cinema&quot;&gt;Direct cinema&lt;/a&gt;, the feeling of being there captures the audience. There’s is no narration, presenter or the film-maker intervening on screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess is what most people think of when they think of “&lt;em&gt;fly on the wall&lt;/em&gt;”, “&lt;em&gt;pure&lt;/em&gt; Obs doc”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However for it to work, they usually chose &lt;em&gt;crisis situations&lt;/em&gt; where not only the contributors are so engrossed into what they are doing that they forget about the camera, but also some sort of &lt;em&gt;story arc&lt;/em&gt; is guaranted by the upcoming events that will be unfolding in life regardless of the filming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- --&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8TsAnUmIzYY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically this comes from 1960s &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Drew&quot;&gt;Robert Drew&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Leacock&quot;&gt;Richard Leacock&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/D._A._Pennebaker&quot;&gt;D.A.Pennebaker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_and_David_Maysles&quot;&gt;Albert and David Maysels&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frederick_Wiseman&quot;&gt;Fedrick Wiseman&lt;/a&gt;, combining a journalistic approach with documentary film making, by making the most out of the equipment that was been reengineered at the time, to be more portable (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Nonfiction-Film-Critical-History-Expanded/dp/0253207061/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1497372250&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=9780253207067&quot;&gt;Barsam 1992, p.305&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allowed to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“to combine Flaherty’s engaging style – a marriage of cinematic narrative conventions to footage based on ‘discovery’- with the unobtrusive recording method”. - &lt;a href=&quot;http://books.google.co.uk/books?id=JLELAQAAMAAJ&amp;amp;q=inauthor:%22Dave+Saunders%22&amp;amp;dq=inauthor:%22Dave+Saunders%22&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=d1VaU8OjIqPa0QWHuICQCw&amp;amp;ved=0CFAQ6AEwBQ&quot;&gt;Saunders 2007, p.9&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cinema-verite&quot;&gt;Cinema Verite&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cin%C3%A9ma_v%C3%A9rit%C3%A9&quot;&gt;Cinema Verite&lt;/a&gt; inspired by Vertov, combined interview, biographical format, portraits of city life, and the focus was on ordinary people in their daily life. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://books.google.co.uk/books?id=z7p36FdLYdIC&amp;amp;lpg=PP1&amp;amp;dq=Nonfiction-Film-Critical-R-M-Barsam%2Fdp%2F0253207061&amp;amp;pg=PP1#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;Barsam 1992, p.301&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Major players were &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pierre_Perrault&quot;&gt;Pierre Perrault&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chris_Marker&quot;&gt;Chris Marker&lt;/a&gt;, Mario Ruspoli, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jacques_Rozier&quot;&gt;Jacques Rozier&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jean_Rouch&quot;&gt;JeanRouch&lt;/a&gt;. In the verite style, the sound was sync ,thanks to lightweight equipment. Editing was chronological rather then striving for a dramatic effect (&lt;a href=&quot;http://books.google.co.uk/books?id=z7p36FdLYdIC&amp;amp;lpg=PP1&amp;amp;dq=Nonfiction-Film-Critical-R-M-Barsam%2Fdp%2F0253207061&amp;amp;pg=PP1#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;Barsam 1992, 303&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jean-Pierre_Beauviala&quot;&gt;Jean-Pierre Beauviala&lt;/a&gt;, invented &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sync_sound&quot;&gt;crystal synchronization&lt;/a&gt;, freeing the camera from its connection to the tape recorder, creating the Aton Cameras. &lt;a href=&quot;http://books.google.co.uk/books?id=z7p36FdLYdIC&amp;amp;lpg=PP1&amp;amp;dq=Nonfiction-Film-Critical-R-M-Barsam%2Fdp%2F0253207061&amp;amp;pg=PP1#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;Barsam 1992, p.302&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jean Rouch uses the camera as a catalyst, incorporating interviews and improvisation as tools. To gain insight into hidden thought - the consciousness of the subject – interventions were employed to guide the participants both inside their inner world, but also stimulating their curiosity for one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the main motivations that led Rouch and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edgar_Morin&quot;&gt;Morin&lt;/a&gt; to be on-camera participants while directing the film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an extract from &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chronique_d&#39;un_%C3%A9t%C3%A9&quot;&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Chronicle of a summer&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/a&gt;, and an interviewwith Jean Rouch. Showing the opening scene where they discuss the implications of film-making with the main contributor Marcelline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“But I wonder if it is possible to film a conversation naturally with a camera present” - Jean Rouch, Chronicle of a summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;!-- Chronicle of a summer find scene where Marcelline walks alone
tmp use this extract --&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Pxk-fg771r8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 1961 film “&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chronique_d&#39;un_%C3%A9t%C3%A9&quot;&gt;Chronique d’une ete&lt;/a&gt;”(“Chronicle of a summer”), started off with a camera that weighted 30 to 50 kilos. This restricted them to shooting from a fixed camera. And halfway through filming, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michel_Brault&quot;&gt;Michel Brault&lt;/a&gt; brought the first lapel mic, and 10 mm camera to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jean_Rouch&quot;&gt;Jean Rouch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best example of the freedom of movement allowed by this type of technology is &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/H9MSD-zmdB8&quot;&gt;the scene where Marceline iswalking through the Place de la Concorde&lt;/a&gt;. She has a recorder and microphone under her coat, and although Rouch and Moran are not aware of what she is saying, they can decide to move the camera,further away, to increase the dramatic effect of the framing. Rouch’s car was used as a dolly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However this focus on the inner word of the subjects in cinema verite has been criticized as self- reflexive, in danger of implying that the only possible film was “&lt;em&gt;was the one about how that film was made.&lt;/em&gt;” (&lt;a href=&quot;http://books.google.co.uk/books?id=t0SePgAACAAJ&amp;amp;dq=Winston,+2008.+Claiming+the+Real&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=AmdaU4KADbHI0AXLi4DQBA&amp;amp;redir_esc=y&quot;&gt;Winston 2008, p.197&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![](https://ytimg.googleusercontent.com/vi/S0dOLHemSgs/0.jpg)
--&gt;

&lt;!-- What is Cinéma Vérité? - Chronicle of a Summer --&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/S0dOLHemSgs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As she so eloquently puts it in this interview, Jean Rouch’s underlying assumption about &lt;em&gt;Truth&lt;/em&gt; is that people reveal their “real” self when performing in rituals, in this case the filming ritual done in the cinema verite way, as opposed to when they go about their daily life unaware of being filmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in finding out more about these two movements, you should check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cin%C3%A9ma_V%C3%A9rit%C3%A9:_Defining_the_Moment&quot;&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Cinema Verite, Defining the moment&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![tmp](https://ytimg.googleusercontent.com/vi/-tZ9jy8v4qs/0.jpg) --&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-tZ9jy8v4qs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;!-- https://youtu.be/HcMvTzlq-iE --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cinema vérité style finds his legacy in the more recent more mainstream films by &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Moore&quot;&gt;Michael Moore&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Morgan_Spurlock&quot;&gt;Morgan spur lock&lt;/a&gt;, but is definitely worth knowing about the British NFTS tradition of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nick_Broomfield&quot;&gt;Nick Broomfield&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Molly_Dineen&quot;&gt;Molly Dineen&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kim_Longinotto&quot;&gt;Kim Longinotto&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d recommend to watch: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rough_Aunties&quot;&gt;Rough Aunties&lt;/a&gt;“(trailer) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sisters_in_Law&quot;&gt;“Sisters in law”&lt;/a&gt; by Kim Longinotto &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Heart_of_the_Angel&quot;&gt;The Heart of the Angel&lt;/a&gt; and “Geri” by Molly Dineen, &amp;gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kurt_%26_Courtney&quot;&gt;Kurt &amp;amp; Courtney&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soldier_Girls&quot;&gt;Soldier Girls&lt;/a&gt;, “&lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/0EGCFr2jLpU&quot;&gt;a time comes&lt;/a&gt;”, and “&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tracking_Down_Maggie&quot;&gt;Tracking Down Maggie&lt;/a&gt;” by Nick Broomfield. Check out this interview with the latest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![tmp](https://ytimg.googleusercontent.com/vi/hwYqnjn7Z-E/0.jpg) --&gt;

&lt;!-- find nick broomfield interview --&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hwYqnjn7Z-E&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very interesting point he makes, and you can see how it then raises ethical questions, and gives ethical editorial responsibility to the film-maker. We’ll get back to this point, but for now let’s consider Michael Moore’s approach.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;!-- ? --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We like non-fiction and we live in fictitious times. - Michael Moore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To take this issue a step further I’d strongly recommend to watch &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Manufacturing_Dissent&quot;&gt;“Manufacturing dissent”&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Tdgk-JFVhvk&quot;&gt;watch&lt;/a&gt;), see trailer below, where film-maker Debbie Melnyk criticise Michael More for “bending” the facts in some of his docs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However before doing so, to avoid spoilers you should probably watch “&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roger_%26_Me&quot;&gt;Roger and Me&lt;/a&gt;”(&lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/WQXYAUql6tI&quot;&gt;trailer&lt;/a&gt;), “&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bowling_for_Columbine&quot;&gt;Bowling for Colombine&lt;/a&gt;”(&lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/fAouWXzi-1Q&quot;&gt;watch&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fahrenheit_9/11&quot;&gt;Fahrenheit 9/11&lt;/a&gt;” &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/cY0OCdHICCo&quot;&gt;watch&lt;/a&gt; to avoid a spoiler alert, and put the criticism more into context.. if you haven’t already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Manufacturing dissent tailer --&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/r3IUU7a4wB0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;verner-herzogs-concept-of-aesthetic-truth&quot;&gt;Verner Herzog’s concept of “Aesthetic truth”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s documentaries most productions will use a mixture of direct cinema and cinema verite, leaning more towards one or the other, and most often aiming to do interviews, mixed with &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Actuality_film&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;actuality&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Most amazing combination of this I’ve seen on Tv recently is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b03ytxmh/episodes/guide&quot;&gt;BBC3 Life and death row series&lt;/a&gt;. What I like about it is it does not recur to narration led voice over. It strikes the right balance between interviews and actuality, using those to drive the narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Life and Death row BBC3 trailer --&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iDsN--mRHho&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it then becomes very useful to understand &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Werner_Herzog&quot;&gt;Werner Herzog&lt;/a&gt; idea of &lt;em&gt;aesthetic truth&lt;/em&gt; and how for him boundaries between documentaries and fiction are therefore very blurred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Before we do so let’s consider this interview I made for the BBC academy college of production with John Douglas one of the directors of one of the episode of the Life and Death Row Series I already mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- John douglas bbc interview --&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/128057278&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key take away here is the emphasis on the relationship with the contributors and representing your understanding of their truth without making it about you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to Herzog, his concept of aesthetic truth. Which is something behiond the actuality and the factual description of the event, it is its manipulation to represent a higher truth of the moment to shade light on elements that would other wise be missed (&lt;a href=&quot;http://books.google.co.uk/books?id=ydN_2oj8M0wC&amp;amp;dq=Herzog+%26+Cronin&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=x1haU73sK-ic0QXB7YHYDA&amp;amp;redir_esc=y&quot;&gt;Herzog Cronin 2002, p.238&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in his words:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So for me, the boundary between fiction and ‘documentary’ simply does not exist; they are all just films. Both take ‘facts’, characters, stories and play with them in the same kind of way. I actually consider Fitzcarraldo my best ‘documentary’. So I fight against cinema verite because it reaches only the most banal level of understanding of everything around us. I know that by making a clear distinction between ‘fact’ and ‘truth’ in my films, I am able to penetrate into a deeper stratum of truth most films do not even notice. The deep inner truth inherent in cinema can be discovered only by not being bureaucratically, politically and mathematically correct. In other words, I start to invent and play with the ‘facts’ as we know them. Through invention, through imagination, through fabrication, I become more truthful than the little bureau- crats. This is an idea that will become clearer when we discuss some of the later films like Bells from the Deep and Lessons of Darkness. - &lt;a href=&quot;http://books.google.co.uk/books?id=ydN_2oj8M0wC&amp;amp;dq=Herzog+%26+Cronin&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=x1haU73sK-ic0QXB7YHYDA&amp;amp;redir_esc=y&quot;&gt;Herzog Cronin 2002, p.240&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking about “&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Little_Dieter_Needs_to_Fly&quot;&gt;little dieter’s needs to fly&lt;/a&gt;” (&lt;a href=&quot;http://books.google.co.uk/books?id=gQg7AAAAQBAJ&amp;amp;lpg=PP1&amp;amp;dq=The%20Cinema%20of%20Werner%20Herzog%3A%20Aesthetic%20Ecstasy%20and%20Truth&amp;amp;pg=PP1#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=The%20Cinema%20of%20Werner%20Herzog:%20Aesthetic%20Ecstasy%20and%20Truth&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;Herzog 2007&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Herzog says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We were very careful about editing and stylizing Dieter’s reality. He had to become an actor playing himself. Everything in the film is authentic Dieter, but to intensify him it is all re-orchestrated, scripted and rehearsed. - (&lt;a href=&quot;http://books.google.co.uk/books?id=ydN_2oj8M0wC&amp;amp;dq=Herzog+%26+Cronin&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=x1haU73sK-ic0QXB7YHYDA&amp;amp;redir_esc=y&quot;&gt;Herzog Cronin 2002, p.265&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally I don’t find the re-orchestrating and scripting of events very interesting in itself, but the Idea of representing a moment that is artificially reconstructed, to fabricate and reproduce emotions and feelings that belong to that moment, it is nonetheless quiet compelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![tmp](https://ytimg.googleusercontent.com/vi/1KQSgcAcNpo/0.jpg) --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an extract from a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b007ght1&quot;&gt;BBC Imagine&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Yentob&quot;&gt;Alan Yentob&lt;/a&gt; Series episode &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/imagine/episode/werner_herzog.shtml&quot;&gt;‘Werner Herzog: Beyond Reason’&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![tmp](https://ytimg.googleusercontent.com/vi/ppe12Cd1yuA/0.jpg) --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alan Yentob asking Herzog about the decision of subsequently making a feature film out Dieter’s story, which was then called &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rescue_Dawn&quot;&gt;Rescue Dawn&lt;/a&gt;, raises the question about choosing documentary over fiction, which I find Is an interesting point for debate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Facts and reality some time are quiet often note enough. You need a Enhancement an intensification of it. Some sort of, an essential version of things to make things transparent - Herzog&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;!-- Alan Yentob interview iwth Herzog for BBC imagine --&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ppe12Cd1yuA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance you take a film like &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/127_Hours&quot;&gt;127 hours&lt;/a&gt;, it could have been a docudrama, in the style of [touching the void](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Touching_the_Void_(film), but Danny Boyle would argue that an actor performing is bests at re-creating the truth and getting the audience into the cinematic story. Vs making a docu-drama.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think there’s a clear cut answer to this question, and it mostly would depend on the story, and the film-maer skills and sensibility. But none the less I agree with the point raised in Imagine that “Rescue Dawn” ended up being more of a documentary because of how literally was reconstructing very detail without leaving room for imagination and interpretation while, “Little Dieter’s needs to fly” was more of a work of fiction (in a good way) because of the performance and re-enactment, which I find interesting food for thought, especially if you think about Jean Rouch idea of performance in rituals being the time where people are their “real” selves, which we mentioned earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key point Herzog make however is this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It was my job as the director to translate and edit his thoughts into something profound and cinematic. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://books.google.co.uk/books?id=ydN_2oj8M0wC&amp;amp;dq=Herzog+%26+Cronin&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=x1haU73sK-ic0QXB7YHYDA&amp;amp;redir_esc=y&quot;&gt;Herzog &amp;amp; Cronin 2002, p.265&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, this also means that sometimes you’d avoid including material that could have great “dramatic impact”, because it is not the right thing to do both for ethics considerations and for the story.See Werner Herzog explaining it in his words in regards to the decision not to include the recording of the final moments of Timothy Treadwell, and his partner being eaten by a bear in “Grizly Man”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It [the audio recording] was so terrifying and horrifying that it was immediatly clear it was not going ot be in the moview […] and ofcourse there is a responsability that as a film-maker you have. because you’d violate the right and the dignity and death o these two individuals, you just don’t do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;!-- Werner Herzog on Grizly man not using the clip where you can hear the death --&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/n0bCcijSqbA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However it is an important pivotal moment in the story, and Herzog, cleaverly finds another way to include it, indirectly through an interview with the doctor who performed the autopsy and had listened to the tape, and who can describes it. As well as through filming himself listening to it, while talking to one of the key contributors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Grizzly Man - Doctor interview about the tape --&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5SJiOZdAWco&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d close this section with a good &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/40147443&quot;&gt;interview with Verner Herzog about one of his latest films “Into the Abyss”&lt;/a&gt; where he talks about his process, coincidentally about death row as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Fourth &amp; Main: Werner Herzog on filmmaking -vimeo --&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/40147443&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/40147443&quot;&gt;Fourth &amp;amp; Main: Werner Herzog on filmmaking&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/esperanzajimenez&quot;&gt;Esperanza Jim&amp;eacute;nez&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; --&gt;

&lt;!-- Fourth &amp; Main: Werner Herzog on filmmaking -youtube --&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QxxEHlQdp78&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also consider how this applies to other forms of documentaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/214023666&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;some-more-docs-you-should-watch-are&quot;&gt;Some more docs you should watch are:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;girzly-man&quot;&gt;Girzly Man&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herzog’s”&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grizzly_Man&quot;&gt;Girzly Man&lt;/a&gt;”, defenetly worth a&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/q8MjDyfcMmU&quot;&gt;watch&lt;/a&gt; if you haven’t seen it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Girzly Man trailer --&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uWA7GtDmNFU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;!-- ![tmp](https://ytimg.googleusercontent.com/vi/gWycuaWJFCM/0.jp) --&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;thin-blue-line&quot;&gt;Thin blue line&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Errol_Morris&quot;&gt;Errol Morris&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Thin_Blue_Line_(1988_film)&quot;&gt;“Thin blue line”&lt;/a&gt; trailer. definitely worth a &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/zUJfrW1hNBk&quot;&gt;watch&lt;/a&gt;. For a great example of plot driven narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &gt;Errol Morris trailer --&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dNL5A4D0G4g&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;!-- ![tmp](https://ytimg.googleusercontent.com/vi/Mnlq0TurT3c/0.jpg) --&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;touching-the-void&quot;&gt;Touching the void&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Touching_the_Void&quot;&gt;“Touching the void”&lt;/a&gt; I saw this when I was 16 at the cinema and is what eventually got me into documentaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Touching the void trailer --&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7Mcdw79l5fQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;searching-for-sugar-man&quot;&gt;Searching for Sugar man&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;!-- ![tmp](https://ytimg.googleusercontent.com/vi/EIawNRm9NWM/0.jpg) --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Searching_for_Sugar_Man&quot;&gt;“Searching for Sugar man”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Searching for Sugar man touching the void trailer --&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QL5TffdOQ7g&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this great interview with the film-maker, Malik Bendjelloul, about the behind the scene making of. Working with contributors and establishing trust and commitment. (watch the film first tho).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;!-- Searching for Sugar Man: Making of (Malik Bendjelloul and Sixto Rodríguez) VOSE --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7jbDKvuwB2s&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I want to stress it doesn’t have always to be some sort of reconstruction of something that happened in the past, like these last examples would suggest, for instance “&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Encounters_at_the_End_of_the_World&quot;&gt;Encounters at the End of the World&lt;/a&gt;”(&lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/MImYM87jOtU&quot;&gt;Trailer&lt;/a&gt;) or “&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Into_the_Abyss_(film)&quot;&gt;Into the Abyss&lt;/a&gt;”(&lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/5uV1_Yc8OSw&quot;&gt;trailer&lt;/a&gt;) by Herzog deal with unfolding events in the present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose these last example because they are films were, taking for granted that the camera is not objective, the question is then shifted on what are the best way to use all the multi-sensory element of the film-making medium to reconstruct the truth of the moment of the story you are trying to tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly I think that “Into the Abyss” by Herzog I’d say it’s in a more cinema verite style contrasted with the BBC “life and death row series” which I persoanlly think hits more of a sweet spot between the two styles (direct cinema/cinema verite)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-all-about-story&quot;&gt;It’s all about story&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None the less, it’s all about story, not as hard and fast rules, but as principles, which you’d need to know about to be able to break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the reason why I say this is that this last point overshadows to a certain extent the previous schools of thoughts, in the sense that once you’ve figured out what the possible story is, then you can work out the best way to tell it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure it’s a given that story telling and story crafting might come easier to some, but none the less it’s a craft, and as such it can be learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And whit this thought in mind I’ll leave you with a clip from &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adaptation_(film)&quot;&gt;Adaptation&lt;/a&gt; where &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_McKee&quot;&gt;Robert Mckee&lt;/a&gt; answers to the question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“What if the writer is attempting to create a story where nothing much happens?[…] more of a reflection of the real world?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;!-- Mckee in adaptation --&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/o2fz_elzjF4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 21:41:08 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>//2017/09/04/2014-04-28-what-you-need-to-know-about-documentary/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//2017/09/04/2014-04-28-what-you-need-to-know-about-documentary/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 Lessons from building video product tools in the newsroom.</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a unique background in Anthropology, Documentary film, and computer&lt;br /&gt;
science, I have developed a skill set of applying my skills and knowledge collectively and creatively. This article is to share the 10 lessons I learned from the development of autoEdit, and walked through how a mixed approach that combines lean, user-centered design and anthropological insights with key computer science techniques,  such as mapping the problem domain and component-based design, can be instrumental in developing products that gain user traction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016 I did a 10-month Knight-Mozilla Fellowship organised by Open News with the Vox Media products team in New York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My interest was to explore possibilities for open source tools to help streamline the video production process. After spending a month interviewing and observing video producers across Vox Media, I narrowed my focus down to creating an application that enables more efficient and accessible video editing of interviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final product is autoEdit (Passarelli 2016a), a Mac OS X desktop app that creates automatic transcription from a video or audio file. The user can make text selections and export those selections as a video sequence to the editing software of choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The success of autoEdit was beyond my expectation - it was downloaded over 700 times within the first three months after its launch. It is currently being used by video producers and journalists across the Vox Media brands, at the Financial Times, CUNY Journalism School, Holocaust Memorial Museum, and many other companies and organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following are 10 lessons I learned from building video product tools in the newsroom. The knowledge and expertise that lead me to approach product design the way I do is the result of my unusual background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My education background includes a B.A. in Anthropology from Goldsmiths, University of London, a MA in Documentary Films from London College of Communication, and a Msc in Computer Science from University College London. My professional background is also a unique mix, I worked in documentary production for BBC, channel 4, and discovery channel, I also had the opportunity to work as a newsroom developer at The Times &amp;amp; Sunday Times in London, where I created quickQuote, a tool that automatically generates interactive video quotes, which won Guardian’s Student Media Startup of the year award in 2015, and worked with the Guardian Video team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the following section, I am going to distill the key takeaways for journalists and developers interested in using user-centered design and rapid prototyping to create products that gain user traction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;user-research&quot;&gt;User Research&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest challenges when doing research to develop a new product is how to get useful actionable intel from users while iteratively developing a prototype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s consider a few key ideas that can help when defining a course of action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lean methodology, pioneered by Eric Ries(Ries 2011), defines an approach to startup and product development initially inspired by the Toyota quick cycle of manufacturing. The focus is on learning, and to iteratively define and test hypothesis to expand understanding of the users and the problem we are trying to solve, rather than on building and deploying a polished product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This goes hand in hand with the idea that there are going to be early adopters that you should spend some time identifying as a defined group and focus your initial research on (Blank and Dorf 2012) .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of “participant observation” is a key element of ethnographic research in anthropology. In social sciences context you don’t just observe, measure and quantify, instead, you need a better way to gather qualitative insights in a rigorous way. Participant observations consist in embedding yourself with the subjects you are studying, taking part in their routines and activities to better understand the world from their point of view, and see what that reveals to you about their knowledge systems and beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As anthropologist Bill Watson, from Kent University, often says, anthropological research has also a strong emphasis on looking at “what people do do, and not what they say they do”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Closely linked with these ideas is the concept of “The Mum test” (Fitzpatrick 2013) . In a nutshell, it says that to get actionable insights to the users you have to root the questions in the past. Using past behavior as more reliable predictor of future decisions. And avoid asking leading questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example if you want to figure out if your users would be interested in using automated transcriptions as a part of their video workflow, Rather than asking “Would you use an app that does X &amp;amp; Y?” first things first, you’d have to learn about their current workflow. “Tell me about the last project you worked on, what was that like from start to finish?”. It is then down to you to drill down to the granularity that gives you the most insights. Then you can ask what the biggest bottleneck is and what the users have done to try and simplify things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In user-centered design approach, building personas should not feel like a chore. Personas are abstract representations of users that embodies some of the common characteristics shared across your pool of early adopters. These are useful in the development and prototyping stage, when defining non-functional requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, asking the users about their work, and what gives them the most satisfaction and what the most tedious part is, is also a great way to get a more rounded sense of who they are and how they think about things. This will also come in handy when considering how to position the product to them in a relatable way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, anthropologists would encourage you to have a healthy distrusts for questionnaires as a research methodology to gather insights. However, if you use the “Mum Test” when phrasing the questions, it can be a useful tool to identify early adopters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-a-domain-expert-but-if-you-are-not-thats-ok-too&quot;&gt;Be a domain expert, but if you are not that’s ok too.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A domain expert is someone who has expertise in a certain field, knows and understands the intricacies of contradictory and conflicting theories in that field, and can juggle those in their mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, a youtuber might be an expert in doing social videos, but if they don’t know about ethics and other epistemological implications of the medium, they might not be a domain expert in documentary production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not a domain expert in the area where you are looking to use user-centered design to build a successful product, that’s ok too, there’s a few ways you can make up for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have defined the domain you are going to be exploring, the first thing to figure out is what are considered as best practices, “expert view” on the topic. For instance in the area of using transcriptions for video production, a paper-edit is still considered as the best practice although having fallen out of fashion because of the tedious and time-consuming process in its analogue form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also need to identify out who is regarded as expert, what are the different school of thoughts, etc. Then as a separate step, find out how your users feel about these experts and school of thoughts, which one they respect, which one they dismiss, and why. For example, in the case of the paper-editing workflow, most video producers either do a simplified variation of it, or don’t do it because it is too time consuming. While sometimes video editors dismiss it as working with text not being visual enough for their liking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Observe and learn from your users. Don’t take their word at face value, they might not always know what’s best for them. In this sense there is a strong parallel to documentary production where you have to research, analyse, interpret and draw your own informed conclusion to define a course of action. For example one of the feedback I had from a video producer at Vox about autoEdit is that it “Goes above and beyond what I thought was possible”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-language-agnostic&quot;&gt;Be language agnostic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a technologist, you should figure out the best technology to use for the problem you are trying to solve and to factor in the learning curve that comes with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In computer science domain, It makes your life a lot easier if you have a focus on understanding the evergreen underlying knowledge, as it moves a lot slower than the latest hip framework that changes every 3 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tools and framework that we use shape the mental models we create to solve problems (Cook 2017), and some might be more suited than others. For instance, in the first version of autoEdit (Passarelli 2016a) I used ruby on rails with SQL as a database. This lead me to model the transcription after a captions, srt file, with line level granularity, which had severe limitation when trying to select text at word level. However in autoEdit2, when working with node and nosql databases, it was easier to reason at a word level granularity and enable more possibility for digital paper-editing (Passarelli 2016b).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the popular saying goes “if you only have a hammer everything becomes a nail”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, Eric Ries has also argued that, in line with user-centered design you should also start with the users and the problem they are facing rather than trying to fit a specific technology to a specific problem (Ries 2011).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;map-the-problem-domain&quot;&gt;Map the problem domain&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also found it particularly helpful to map the problem domain as a strategy to deal with ever changing requirements (Winder and Roberts 2006).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A problem domain is the context in which a particular problem exists. For example, the problem domain in which a specific route plan exists is that of maps, route planning, travelling and strategies for moving around. Critically, the problem domain is relatively stable, changing only slowly, while specific problems to be solved are transient and change regularly. If you are able to capture the problem domain as the core of the design of your program, then the program code is likely to be more stable, more reusable and more easily adaptable to specific problems as they come and go.” (Winder and Roberts 2006, 351)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Consider wanting to know how to travel from A to B. You could ask someone for a route plan and get a list of instructions containing statements such as ‘go to the end of the road, turn left, then turn right at the third turning on the left’, and so on. With a basic understanding of how each statement is interpreted (e.g. how to count turnings to find the third on the left), you can follow the instructions and get to your destination”.(Winder and Roberts 2006, 354)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A given route plan may work but it is very specific. To find out how to travel to a different destination you have to go and ask for a new list of instructions every time you want to travel. An alternative strategy for dealing with your travelling problem is to make use of a map. This will allow you to travel between any two points on the map and do your own route planning. The route planning can even be done while you are travelling. There is a cost for using the map, you have to learn how to read and interpret it, as well as develop strategies for planning routes. However, in the longer term the benefits more than outweigh the initial learning costs. Moreover, much more of the map strategy is reusable—it is easy to transfer the solution strategy from one problem to the next.” (Winder and Roberts 2006, 355)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-component-based-design&quot;&gt;use component-based design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another helpful technique is that of component-based design when writing the code of your program (Winder and Roberts 2006)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A component is typically implemented by a small collection of classes, with one class acting as an interface to the component. Rather than designing a program from scratch, it can be built out of a set of predefined components which are linked together with small amounts of new code. This approach is termed component-based design. The connections between components are enabled using the mechanisms of inheritance, interfaces and dynamic binding. Users of the component make use of the public interface to call the component’s methods but need not be aware of the details of the component implementation.” (Winder and Roberts 2006, 265)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking in terms of reusable components has several advantages. For instance autoEdit “front end” is written in web technologies in such a way that the demo on the project website is the same code but with a hard coded database. This means that if I were to make a web version of the app I could reuse that part with minimal adjustments. It ultimately comes down to making a judgement call between premature optimization vs being strategic. Often a thin line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-an-rd-approach&quot;&gt;Use an R&amp;amp;D Approach&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have got some findings from initial user research, you are ready to take the next step to identify, learn, and understand possible workflows. Then you can treat it almost like a lego project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, for autoEdit, an understanding of the paper-editing workflow and how the users relate to that and/or a variation of it was crucial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a better feel for this, I run a series of workshop on paper-editing, where participants were learning interview story crafting and I would get the type of insights you normally get through focus groups, focusing on the underlying workflow and not the app itself. (Passarelli 2017) (Passarelli 2016c)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have the workflow figured out, next step is to divide it into parts. Of those parts identify the granularity of what are the components that make up that part. For those components, find out which ones you have available and to what degree you are familiar with their workings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as which ones you don’t know. Priority is given to the ones you don’t know to verify how they work and whether they make the whole possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have all the components you look at the interfaces and the communication between that, do you need to do any conversion or adjustment eg to get the output of one as input of the other etc.. This also helps you to think about data models representations that are most suited for the overall system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows to work on parts and components in isolation and then combined them. Don’t leave the combining and integration experiments too late tho because sometimes they are just as important as the building blocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Threat everything as an hypothesis and prioritise which one to be tested first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;learn-how-to-formulate-questions-as-a-way-to-get-over-unexpected-roadblocks-during-development&quot;&gt;Learn how to formulate questions as a way to get over unexpected roadblocks during development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not a question if you are going to get stuck, but rather a matter of when. It is therefore important to think about how you are going to get yourself out of it and use your time productively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Face with an unexpected problem, think about what you know, the limits of what you know, what you don’t know and the limits of what you don’t know. Then describe what you know about the current setup, and inner workings. Describe the symptoms of what’s not working as expected. Write it all down. This takes you already half way to find a solution, as you can now share it and communicate with others more efficiently when asking for advice. It’s important to also spend some time identifying the right vocabulary to express the problem. You can then iteratively make hypothesis about the root cause, and run experiments to test it out. This will help you narrow it down until you find a solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-brave-like-pixar&quot;&gt;Be brave like Pixar&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I once watched this documentary about Pixar, The Pixar Story (Iwerks 2007), and was fascinated by how Toy Story team had the courage to throw away all the work just a couple of days before deadline, and started over from a blank canvas because the story and its main character was not quite working out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might seem daunting but If you had mapped the problem domain, followed component-based architecture and user-centered design, you really are just throwing away only the material representation of your ideas. And you are actually in a good place to start over, with all the excitement and liberating anticipation of a blank canvas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;human-vs-machine&quot;&gt;Human vs machine?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the context of where to draw the line in the automation debate in replacing people’s jobs, especially with the recent buzz around AI, in studies that compared the performance of a team of humans, a team of “machines” and a mixed team of humans and computers, have found that the mixed team seems to consistently achieve the highest result (Allègre L and Matthias 2013).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been dwelling on the ethical issues around the development of autoEdit, for a while now, there is a possibility that, especially if combined with more advanced cognitive services, it could replace video editors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all IBM Watson can edit a video trailer (Smith 2016), with pretty good results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are already examples of Earthquake bulletins written by machines without human review and the same has happened for economic reports (Jenkin 2016).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this context It’s important to recognise that there is always a bias, of some sort, gender, race etc.. of whoever wrote the algorithm (Devlin 2016) .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the current version of autoEdit, the aim was to remove the tedious parts of the paper-editing workflow to enable the video producers to concentrate on the story crafting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;convenience-trumps-quality-every-day-of-the-week&quot;&gt;Convenience trumps quality every day of the week&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In certain contexts of automation, convenience seems to win over quality every day of the week. Increasingly leading to a polarized scenario with either high volume production with low quality output or low quality production with high volume distribution, and no room for anything in between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example is the use of text to speech to to do voice over of videos, where quality of the speech to text services is not as good as human narrators but can scale faster and cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the interest of adding value for the users, I would argue it is your job as an application developer to address both convenience and quality. Identify convenience hooks to get traction with your users, but be concerned about raising quality of the output. Don’t expect an increase in quality to be sufficient for new user adoption, however counterintuitive this might seem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, with autoEdit the 5 minutes turnaround time for transcriptions is a very important cutoff point that was instrumental in gaining traction with early adopters. And even automated speech to text service alone is not as good quality compared to transcriptions services with 24 hours turnaround time with services that provide human or human + machine transcriptions. But the convenience wins over quality. And therefore some users will put up with the decrease in quality of the transcription they get for the added value of a fast turnaround.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we explored 10 lessons I learned from the development of autoEdit, and walked through how a mixed approach that combines lean, user-centered design and anthropological insights with key computer science techniques, such as mapping the problem domain and component-based design, can be instrumental in developing products that gain user traction. I would like to encourage readers to think deeper and further about how they can leverage some of the techniques I have explained to add value and increase quality of their products for their users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allègre L,. Hadida, and Seifert Matthias. 2013. “3 Humans + 1 Computer = Best Prediction.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2013/05/3-humans-1-computer-best-prediction&quot;&gt;https://hbr.org/2013/05/3-humans-1-computer-best-prediction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blank, Steve, and Bob Dorf. 2012. The Startup Owner’s Manual: The Step-By-Step Guide for Building a Great Company. 1 edition. Pescadero, Calif: K &amp;amp; S Ranch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cook, Blaine. 2017. “Annotations Models.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://pietropassarelli.gitbooks.io/textav/problem-domains/d83d-dd2a-2705-2b07-fe0f-annotations-models.html&quot;&gt;https://pietropassarelli.gitbooks.io/textav/problem-domains/d83d-dd2a-2705-2b07-fe0f-annotations-models.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Devlin, Hannah. 2016. “Discrimination by Algorithm: Scientists Devise Test to Detect AI Bias Technology The Guardian.”&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/dec/19/discrimination-by-algorithm-scientists-devise-test-to-detect-ai-bias&quot;&gt; https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/dec/19/discrimination-by-algorithm-scientists-devise-test-to-detect-ai-bias&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fitzpatrick, Rob. 2013. The Mom Test. 1 edition. CreateSpace Independent Publishing Platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iwerks, Leslie. 2007. “The Pixar Story: Leslie Iwerks: Amazon Digital Services LLC.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Pixar-Story-Leslie-Iwerks/dp/B006DQP64A/ref=sr_1_fkmr0_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1501371860&amp;amp;sr=8-1-fkmr0&amp;amp;keywords=The+Pixar+Story+documentary+dvd&quot;&gt;https://www.amazon.com/Pixar-Story-Leslie-Iwerks/dp/B006DQP64A/ref=sr_1_fkmr0_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1501371860&amp;amp;sr=8-1-fkmr0&amp;amp;keywords=The+Pixar+Story+documentary+dvd&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jenkin, Matthew. 2016. “Written Out of the Story: The Robots Capable of Making the News Guardian Small Business Network The Guardian.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/small-business-network/2016/jul/22/written-out-of-story-robots-capable-making-the-news&quot;&gt;https://www.theguardian.com/small-business-network/2016/jul/22/written-out-of-story-robots-capable-making-the-news&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passarelli, Pietro. 2016a. “autoEdit.” &lt;a href=&quot;www.autoEdit.io&quot;&gt;www.autoEdit.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;———. 2016b. “autoEdit User Manual.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://pietropassarelli.gitbooks.io/autoedit2-user-manual/content/paperediting.html&quot;&gt;https://pietropassarelli.gitbooks.io/autoedit2-user-manual/content/paperediting.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;———. 2016c. “How to Craft Compelling Stories Out of Video Interviews?” &lt;a href=&quot;http://pietropassarelli.com/wip_london_july2016.html&quot;&gt;http://pietropassarelli.com/wip_london_july2016.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;———. 2017. How to Tell Compelling Stories Out of Video Interviews. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gitbook.com/book/pietropassarelli/how-to-tell-compelling-stories-out-of-video-inter/&quot;&gt;https://www.gitbook.com/book/pietropassarelli/how-to-tell-compelling-stories-out-of-video-inter/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ries, Eric. 2011. The Lean Startup: How Today’s Entrepreneurs Use Continuous Innovation to Create Radically Successful Businesses. 1 edition. New York: Crown Business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smith, John R. 2016. “IBM Research Takes Watson to Hollywood with the First ‘Cognitive Movie Trailer’ - THINK Blog.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibm.com/blogs/think/2016/08/cognitive-movie-trailer/&quot;&gt;https://www.ibm.com/blogs/think/2016/08/cognitive-movie-trailer/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winder, Russel, and Graham Roberts. 2006. Developing Java Software. 3 edition. Chichester, UK ; Hoboken, NJ: Wiley.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>//10-lessons-video-tools.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//10-lessons-video-tools.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Opened Captions Annotated article system</title>
        <description>&lt;!-- _draft: more coming soon_ --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pietropassarelli.gitbooks.io/opened-captions-for-annotated-articles&quot;&gt;gitbook notes and video of presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1yI6SkJi-RqV11_fFImfh44iG011hPlgtwNzYcF2P1_U/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;slides from SRCCON’17 presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pietrop/Opened-Captions-for-Annotated-Articles&quot;&gt;github repo that syncs with gitbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also recently made a working proof of concept for an app to replace the rig, to make it easier for the end user to use without the supervision of a newsroom developer. See screenshot below&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/opened_caption_app/opened_caption_annotation_app.png&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot of layout &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>//opened-captions-annotated-article-rig.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//opened-captions-annotated-article-rig.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Captioning app [Working Title]</title>
        <description>&lt;!-- TODO move from  --&gt;

&lt;!-- _draft: more coming soon_ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pbs.twimg.com/media/DF7ytQ7VoAA1ry2.jpg:large&quot; alt=&quot;captioning app screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the &lt;a href=&quot;http://pietropassarelli.com/textAV.html&quot;&gt;textAV&lt;/a&gt; event with a small team we did the &lt;a href=&quot;https://pietropassarelli.gitbooks.io/textav/content/unconference-projects/captioning-workflow-system.html&quot;&gt;requirements gathering &lt;/a&gt; based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pietropassarelli.gitbooks.io/textav/content/remote-presentations/captioning-workflow.html&quot;&gt;Joseph Polizzotto’s presentation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/oTranscribe/oTranscribe&quot;&gt;oTranscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the following weekend I built an app that considerably speeds up and simplify the captioning workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It auto transcribes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It adds punctuation automatically&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User can then correct the text&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It auto segments and aligns to create caption file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;demo&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;http://pietropassarelli.com/captions-maker&quot;&gt;demo here&lt;/a&gt; for demonstration purposes (click &lt;strong&gt;load&lt;/strong&gt; and then &lt;strong&gt;align&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It auto transcribes using speech to text service to give you a first draft, it auto adds the punctuations, you can review and correct, and when you click &lt;strong&gt;align&lt;/strong&gt; it segments and auto  aligns(very fast) to create a caption file (srt but could support more format) similar to youtube captioning editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gives you a preview of the caption file, with clicable timecodes that take you to that point in the video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JPolizzotto&quot;&gt;@JPolizzotto&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/GidsG&quot;&gt;@GidsG&lt;/a&gt; auto transcribe, auto punctuation, auto srt lines alignment... &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/textAV?src=hash&quot;&gt;#textAV&lt;/a&gt;.tech &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/mbW799QYnr&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/mbW799QYnr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Pietro (@pietropassarell) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pietropassarell/status/889321437504385024&quot;&gt;July 24, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>//captioning-app.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//captioning-app.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>textAV event</title>
        <description>&lt;!-- _draft: more coming soon_ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More details &lt;br /&gt;
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://pietropassarelli.gitbooks.io/textav/content/&quot;&gt;Video presentations and notes from event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
- &lt;a href=&quot;http://textAV.tech&quot;&gt;Event website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/view/textav/confirmed-participants&quot;&gt;Line up of participants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://trello.com/b/tyIWiHOE/text-a-v-event-topics&quot;&gt;Trello board with projects&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
- &lt;a href=&quot;http://textav.hyperaud.io/pad&quot;&gt;hyperaud.io repo of the talks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- TODO: add Molly&#39;s post from Source when available.

TODO: add a bit about rational of the event, knowledge share to get people up to speed + unconference to hack on project. 

But not an hackaton, goal to grow and streghten the ecosystem.

 --&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;!--  


&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;What a morning view from &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/x9UQL7s0K4&quot;&gt;https://t.co/x9UQL7s0K4&lt;/a&gt; event space &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/NyuTisch&quot;&gt;@NyuTisch&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/TextAV?src=hash&quot;&gt;#TextAV&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/Y5ixZqk0Bd&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/Y5ixZqk0Bd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Joscha Jaeger (@OpenHypervideo) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/OpenHypervideo/status/887660076999335936&quot;&gt;July 19, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Lots of news bout &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PopUpArchive&quot;&gt;@PopUpArchive&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/audiosearchfm&quot;&gt;@audiosearchfm&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/baileyspace&quot;&gt;@baileyspace&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/textav?src=hash&quot;&gt;#textav&lt;/a&gt;. 💁 &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/9hiTuGMzv4&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/9hiTuGMzv4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dave Rice (@dericed) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dericed/status/887739052182700032&quot;&gt;July 19, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Archive problems with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dericed&quot;&gt;@dericed&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/villereal&quot;&gt;@villereal&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/textav?src=hash&quot;&gt;#textav&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/ByyEa58k2W&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/ByyEa58k2W&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; amymonte (@amymonte) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/amymonte/status/887769074561937408&quot;&gt;July 19, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes here we go: &amp;quot;archive problems&amp;quot; with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dericed&quot;&gt;@dericed&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/villereal&quot;&gt;@villereal&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/textav?src=hash&quot;&gt;#textav&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/KO5yh7MuYP&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/KO5yh7MuYP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Molly Schwartz (@mollyfication) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mollyfication/status/887768871448580096&quot;&gt;July 19, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;judge for yourself &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/5DaekoV4XE&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/5DaekoV4XE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dave Rice (@dericed) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dericed/status/887691814123261952&quot;&gt;July 19, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

--&gt;

&lt;!-- 


Captions burner 
https://voxmedia.github.io/captions_burner/ 
Needs testing with vtt to see if it supports styling. 


 --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>//textAV.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//textAV.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gitbook: How to tell compelling stories out of video interviews</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;draft: more coming soon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;http://pietropassarelli.com/wip_london_july2016.html&quot;&gt;series of workshops&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is &lt;a href=&quot;https://pietropassarelli.gitbooks.io/how-to-tell-compelling-stories-out-of-video-inter/content/paper-editing/key-concepts-in-documentary-theory.html&quot;&gt;a section on documentary representation&lt;/a&gt; that I think it’s interesting/relevant in the accountability debate that has been raised with the new issues around fake news, the increasing need for transparency and interests by the viewers to see the source material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- 


Captions burner 
https://voxmedia.github.io/captions_burner/ 
Needs testing with vtt to see if it supports styling. 


 --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>//paper-edit-gitbook.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//paper-edit-gitbook.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>autoEdit2</title>
        <description>&lt;!-- _draft: more coming soon_ --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://source.opennews.org/articles/video-editing-made-better-introducing-autoedit&quot;&gt;SOURCE: ‘Introducing autoEdit: Video Editing Made Better’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niemanlab.org/2016/10/try-out-this-open-source-tool-for-editing-video-and-audio-transcripts&quot;&gt;NiemanLab: ‘Try out this open source tool for editing video and audio transcripts’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.journalism.co.uk/news/tool-for-journalists-autoedit-to-edit-videos-quicker-using-transcriptions/s2/a684359/&quot;&gt;Journalism.co.uk: ‘Tool for journalists: AutoEdit, to edit videos quicker using transcriptions’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://product.voxmedia.com/2016/11/22/13669486/faster-video-editing&quot;&gt;Vox Media Product Blog: ‘An open source tool for enabling faster, easier editing of video interviews’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rjionline.org/stories/fl171-ibm-watson-speech-to-text&quot;&gt;RJI: ‘FL#171: IBM Watson Speech to Text’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.autoedit.io/img/autoEdit_overview_diagram_1.0.7.png&quot; alt=&quot;autoEdit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- 

http://www.autoedit.io/

- http://www.niemanlab.org/2016/10/try-out-this-open-source-tool-for-editing-video-and-audio-transcripts/ 

- https://www.journalism.co.uk/news/tool-for-journalists-autoedit-to-edit-videos-quicker-using-transcriptions/s2/a684359/

- https://product.voxmedia.com/2016/11/22/13669486/faster-video-editing



TODO: link to computational journalism paper once you publish in blog section

 --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>//autoEdit2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//autoEdit2.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Whistleblower Interview Archive</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;draft: more coming soon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- TODO: add img 


--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/wip_archive/wip_archive_t.png&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot of layout &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tech&quot;&gt;Tech&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is using a modified version of the system that generates the demo site for autoEdit github page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pietrop/WIP_archive&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;README&lt;/code&gt; for more info&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also used &lt;a href=&quot;www.autoEdit.io&quot;&gt;autoEdit&lt;/a&gt; to generate the transcriptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- 


Captions burner 
https://voxmedia.github.io/captions_burner/ 
Needs testing with vtt to see if it supports styling. 


 --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>//wip.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//wip.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>POV Hackaton: &#39;Battle Sound&#39;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;draft: more coming soon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Used autoEdit2 to speed up the  making of the hypertranscript.&lt;br /&gt;
Using github pages, and a google spreadsheet as “backend”, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pietrop/BattleSounds/blob/master/notes.md&quot;&gt;see R&amp;amp;D Notes for more info&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- 
Some notes on what to write about 

TODO: Add video 

 --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>//default.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//default.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Transcriber - prototype</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;draft: more coming soon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Purpose of this working prototype was to test whether users(and which user segment) would be accepting of the quality of the speech to text service by IBM Watson. Before introducing &lt;a href=&quot;http://pietropassarelli.com/autoEdit2.html&quot;&gt;autoEdit 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not a production ready app, but rather a throwaway intermediate project. Altho users kept using it until the introduciton of autoEdit2, you can read &lt;a href=&quot;https://source.opennews.org/articles/video-editing-made-better-introducing-autoedit/&quot;&gt;more about this process here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/voxmedia/Transcriber/master/img/transciber.png&quot; alt=&quot;Transcriber 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/voxmedia/Transcriber/master/img/demo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Transcriber&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- 


Captions burner 
https://voxmedia.github.io/captions_burner/ 
Needs testing with vtt to see if it supports styling. 


 --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>//Transcriber-prototype.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//Transcriber-prototype.html</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
